Hello!
It has been a very long time since I've posted a video.
It's been like a year and a half.
Obviously, it's a bit weird for someone to disappear from the internet for a long
period of time, and then figuring out how to come back is also weird.
So that's the goal of this video, to explain where I've been, what I've been
up to, and where I'm going.
Where I've been is pretty simple.
At first, I was going through a pretty hard time in my life.
I had some pretty bad health issues that showed up, and some personal stuff that
just required me to take a step back.
And I didn't intend for it to be a long step back.
I just intended for it to be a short step back.
Things were pretty bad and ultimately it was just like, okay, I need to figure
this out.
And luckily I did figure it out.
You know, everything's going a lot better now and this year has actually been a
really amazing year.
I've been up to some like really fun, weird stuff that I wouldn't have done
if I was still posting YouTube videos and it's been really great.
But in the background of all of that, I've been thinking, okay, how do I
get back into posting YouTube videos?
And one of the things that I thought about over this period was that I
don't want to be taking half measures with anything that I do in my life.
As many of you will know if you've watched my content for a while, the
videos that I was making for kind of the months leading up to taking my
time off, they weren't really me trying hard, they weren't really creative, they were just
like posting a video for the sake of posting a video because it would have
been awkward to not post a video.
And that's just not what I want to be doing with my life, to be
honest, right?
And it's just kind of trapped that a lot of content creators fall into of
like, okay, well, I just got to keep posting because this is what I do.
For me, I've always felt a little bit reticent about that because it just leads
you into this kind of like slop machine, which is fine if that's the type
of stuff that you want to be doing.
It's just not the type of stuff that I want to be doing.
So as I thought about the type of stuff that I want to be doing
and thought about returning to social media, I realized that what I wanted to do
was try a lot harder at making some really cool content, stuff that I can
throw myself 100% into.
And so in the second half of this year, I worked really hard on a
series that I'm going to be releasing.
It's called Reading My Way Across America.
I went on a really long road trip where I drove from the Atlantic Ocean,
New Bedford, all the way out to the mountains in Denver.
And I visited the sites of eight different great American novels ranging from Moby Dick
to To Kill a Mockingbird to On the Road.
So I visited the places where the novels are set, I followed in the footsteps
of the protagonists, and I tried to understand and analyze what it is that makes
these novels so great.
This is a really fun trip for me and I'm really proud of the content
that I made from that.
Now the way that this content is going to be getting posted on YouTube is
pretty straightforward.
I'm gonna post post the first half right now.
So over the next four days you're going to see four videos.
Then there's going to be about a month and I'll post the second half.
I think it's really cool content and I hope that you think so as well.
I hope that you really enjoy it.
Now in the spirit of not half-assing stuff, I'm also going to be shutting down
Bookshelved by the end of the year, which was the site that I was running
and it's like a book review site and I just did a bad job of
running it.
I'll take that completely on me, especially in this year where I didn't do a
good job and I could have done a much better job.
So I'm gonna just shut it down.
It's the right thing to do.
And so I'm really grateful to everyone who helped with that and everyone who was
a part of that, the community that formed there.
You know, hopefully people enjoyed it and enjoyed some of the conversations that we had.
There was some really great stuff that went on there, but ultimately it's not something
moving forward that I can be focused on, especially if you're gonna be focused on
making really cool seasons of content like this.
So I hope you understand and I'm thankful to everyone who tried it out again.
And then finally, as you might have guessed, the content that I'm going to be
making will look a lot different moving forward.
And the way that I post it might look a lot different moving forward as
well.
I think I'm going to start posting more seasonally where it's like, hey, I'm going
to post a season of content and then I'm going to go off and plan
and film and edit another one and then post that season again.
Rather than doing what most content creators do, which is like, you know, post every
week or post every month.
It's something that I'm gonna experiment with at least, and I'm gonna try it next
year as well with filming a series.
And who knows, maybe that changes in the future.
Maybe I try and do something where it's like spreading it out over a period
of time, because that's how social media usually operates.
But I really like the idea of treating this as it's like a full-fledged production,
and maybe it becomes a full-fledged production in the future.
But I wanted to post this video to show people like, hey, I'm alive, I
appreciate your messages of concern, And it was really nice when I was going through
a hard period to see that.
And I appreciate everyone also respecting my privacy.
Obviously, I post videos to the internet.
I'm a public figure.
But I'm also a deeply private person.
I don't share a lot of details about my personal life.
And if I want to share those things, I will share them.
But ultimately, I think it's really important for me to have a separation there.
So that's pretty much it.
I hope that you really enjoy these videos.
I worked really hard on them.
I think they're pretty sweet.
And if you don't enjoy them, that's okay too.
I just appreciate you taking the time and getting this far in the video.
So, thank you for watching.
I'll see you again tomorrow with the first video of Reading My Way Across America
in New Bedford, Massachusetts with Moby Dick.